Lombard General Insurance's
results are out. Today we will
try to analyze where its results
are currently and how much the company
still has a position to buy its shares. Hello
everyone.
Thank you very much for giving so much love to Youth India Official Channel. Let's start today's
video. First of today's video,
I will talk about the
growth in sales of the company.
Why is the sales growth so much? The
reason is that the company sold around 4012 crores in the month of 2013. Outside the
month of 2024,
it is selling around 20487 crores.
If we talk about operating profit,
we will see that where it used to
run in the minus, that is, it was in a negative
loss of 178 crores, but it is in a
positive position of 2440 crores.
And what I like the most is that in
these two years, its operating profit has increased by 1.5%, which is 1.5%, compared to 2.4% in the year 2012 and 2013.  The
profit margin had fallen a lot,
but it has
helped to raise it again to 12%, which is
a good thing and we hope that
this profit margin will
increase in the future. Along with that, the other income that the company used to have has
reduced a little. But
if we look at its net profit,
we will see more net profit there. And
if we look at the growth of EPS in the company,
we will see that EPS has increased to
35. You can see
that two or three years ago, where
25.89 was going, it went from 35 to 38.
That is, we can see that there is a growth in EPS. In
this case, the company is
continuously paying dividends, and
where 35%, 28%, 26%, but it has been seen that the
company is paying dividends in the last
ten years and five years.  What data is
there for the years? If we talk about sales growth first, we can
see that it has increased at 17% CGR.
If we talk about five years, then it is 13%, that is, in the last
five years, but its sales have seen a slight
drop. The compound
profit growth has been 14%, and in five
years, both sales growth and profit growth are
equal. This is a sudden number.
If we look at the company's CGR in one year,
its stock price is above
40.6%, but it has been seen growing.
We can
see that the company has a return on equity of 18
percent, but I think it is
bad because the return on equity should be above 25%,
although I personally do
not like to see return on equity, because return on equity can be
manipulated by date, but by any date of the company,
and if we look at the balance sheet,
we will see that
equity  With the change of a little two crores in the capital, the
reserves in the company are slowly increasing
and since the company is also paying dividends, there are
possibilities in future expansion.
If we see whether there is short-term borrowing in the company,
we will see that it has already been
repaid, but we can
see that the current outstanding amount of long-term borrowing is outstanding.
If we look at the cash equivalent of the company, we will see that the
company has the
second highest cash of 335 crores. The
reason is that a few years ago, if
I explain the year, we will
see that in 2019 they had a
cash of 402 crores, from there, now they have a
second high of 335 crores, but
they have cash and the company has
also provided loans for the short term,
which is 13073 crores. And
if we
talk about the basic fundamentals of the company, we  I know that
General Insurance works on this and is a
very well diversified company whose
risk management solution is
through multiple distribution channels
and the company was established
in 2001 and did a joint venture with
ICICI Bank and
Fairfax and
if we look at the market cap of the company then we can see that it is
above 81000 crores that is we
can call it a large cap company
if we keep an eye on the current price of the company
we can see that it is around 1649 rupees
but the current price is going on which if
we judge from the intensive value
then we can see that the
stock price is trading at a premium if
we look at the stock p then we can
see that the stock p is going on 423 where the
industry p is going on 416 that is we are
slightly but overbought but we can also
see from the stock p and the company
has debt but 35 crores which is debt
to equity ratio absolutely nothing but
there is cash equivalent  There is an extra of 335 crores
i.e. 300 crores
which is a
positive aspect of a company, I think I have
explained this before, along with that the
company is paying dividend of 25.7%.
Now if you ask me, brother,
if I pay 100 rupees,
how much return can the company generate?
We can see that it can generate a return of 22.5%, so
we can be fairly satisfied with the return on capital.
Moreover, the company has a
very bad current ratio, that is, the
free cash flow of the company is
much less than the current assets and current liabilities.
This is the only bad aspect and
it should be listed so that it is above two and
that will be good. And if we
compare the company with the peer, that is,
with the other companies,
if we talk about the company
comparing its EV by EV with all the other SBI Life Insurance or LIC, then what is its EV by EV?
If we compare EV to EV,
we will see that it is
relatively
undervalued
compared to the rest, besides, FII holding is
quite high, close to 23%, which
I think is a serious level.
If we want to see another thing about the company, the
quick ratio is
very low, which seems to me to be a
bad thing, that is, the company has
current assets compared to current liabilities, but the
company has not bought back
4% since December 2023, which we can see in March 2024. This is
a good aspect, but the strength in the company, the promoters are buying it,
and the company has
taken some of the buyback from DI, above 2%, and some
from retailers, but here the
FIIs have maintained their stake, that is,
we understand that
only
959% of the company's stake is with retailers.
But
we will see the position of this channel too. This channel is
located here. That is,
we can roughly say that below 5% of
people, but retail people, have
invested in these shares. The maximum is
with institutions. That is,
FIIs, DIIs and promoters.
If we come to a conclusion and talk about it, then
two or three things will come out of the conclusion.
One is that the sales growth of the company is a little bit higher.
I think it would have been better if it was a little higher. Along with that, the
company has more CC. The company has cash. Along with that, the
thing that I have another problem with the company is that the
equity capital of the company has increased suddenly. We have to
check that. And along with that, I think that the
profit growth in the company should
increase a little. So, looking at everything, I
understand that the company is
okay for investment. But for the long term,
I will not give it more weightage.
If I buy here.
I definitely won't provide much weight here, but that's all there is to
this company.
See you in the next video. Stay well,
stay healthy, and of course, before you go,
subscribe to the channel.
Thank you for supporting us. Thank
you so much.